# Viacheslav Kolybelkin

### **Senior Software Engineer**

10 years of programming experience in developing applications based on Java, Kotlin and related technologies as standalone applications and microservices. Experienced in the full cycle of software development namely estimation, implementation, automation testing, performance testing/tuning, and support. Wide experience in agile principles along with the practice of leading a team.

### **Contacts**

Phone: +7 909 333 1666

E-Mail: cv@kolybelkin.com

<u>LinkedIn</u>

<u>GitHub</u>

# **Skills**

- Java, Kotlin
- Spring (boot) framework
- Microservices
- Elasticsearch, Redis, PostgreSQL
- Camunda BPM
- Apache Kafka
- · Maven, Gradle
- Keycloak
- ELK, Sentry
- Docker, Kubernetes
- FIX, FAST protocols, libraries
- Agile methodologies: Scrum, Kanban
- JIRA, GitHub, GitLab
- Git

# **Certifications**

- Oracle Certified Professional, Java SE 8 Programmer
- Oracle Certified Associate, Java SE 8 Programmer

# Languages

Russian – Native English – Full Working Proficiency

# Experience

#### Senior Software Engineer / Team lead – Elfin Tech

06/2020 to now

- Ran planning meetings, was in charge of deliverables, managed a team.
- Automated release process and was responsible of it, handled L3 support incidents.
- Completed the project for migrating two old PHP frontends in accordance with new technology stack (ReactJS and Kotlin). Led team of 6 backend and frontend developers.
- Introduced keycloak as a session manager.
- Completed two sub-products from scratch for new bank integrations based on Camunda BPMN.
- Designed and implemented reporting system based on Kafka.
- Implemented a new microservice for calculating statistics.
- Designed and implemented a sub-system for working with history of questionnaire changes.

#### Senior Software Engineer – Epam systems

05/2015 to 06/2020

- Worked on a solution for routing FIX messages (Java, Spring, microservices, Kafka, k8s), led a small backend team, ran scrum meetings.
- Designed and implemented a system from scratch for testing FIX solutions using BDD approach (Cucumber-JVM).
- Implemented a set of small projects to build a custom solution based on the company's FIX library. Participated in design, estimation, presentation sessions.
- Introduced logic for low-latency consuming CME market by order an orderbased data feed in the open-source library.
- Introduced new features in a company's FIX session level library, profiled the code (JMC, VisualVM, perf), implemented performance tests and optimisations, handled L3 level support requests from customers.

# Software Engineer – NetCracker, Exactpro

12/2012 to 05/2015

#### Education

Russia, Saratov State Technical University

Master's Degree in Computer Science.

2009-2014